number one is to hit b which is going to
bring up your blade tool and you can
hover
over your video and select wherever
you'd like to make a cut to make this
even quicker if you hit command b it is
automatically going to cut for you
wherever your playhead is
using command b like this is going to
make a cut on the layer you have
selected but if you want to make a cut
on all the layers on top
of your play head you can do shift
command b
and that is going to make cuts on every
single layer where your play head is at
you got to just press record number two
is to hit a which is going to bring up
your selector tool and from there you
can select the clips that you want to
delete
and you can go ahead and delete those
number three is to hit
l this is going to start your footage
and when you hit it again it's gonna
play back your video
even faster this makes it a lot easier
to watch back your videos at a faster
speed in order for you to save time
when editing freeze frames can be really
cool to add to your videos and it's
really easy in final cut pro 10
all you have to do is hover over the
spot where you want it to freeze
you will select your clip and hit option
f this is going to add in a freeze frame
you can drag it to the left to make it
shorter you can drag it to the right to
make it longer
and when you watch it back your freeze
frame is going to happen and then the
rest of the video is going to continue
on
once the freeze frame is over when
making precise cuts in final cut pro 10
you want to zoom into your timeline so
you can see
everything going on usually what you do
is you go over here you click this
button
and then you can zoom in like this but a
much quicker
way to do this is by hitting command
plus and this is going to zoom
into your timeline and then hitting
command minus is going to zoom out of
your timeline i use this tool all the
time to zoom in and refine my cuts and
zooming in really just makes it a whole
lot easier right here we can see that
our audio is pretty quiet but if you
want to make your audio
louder at a certain point or quieter at
a certain point all you need to do is
hit
r and this is going to pull up the range
selector this is going to work on an
audio or video clip you just need to
select a piece that you want to be
quieter or louder and
from here once that's selected all you
got to do is drag up
on that audio making it louder or you
can make it
softer you can then drag these keyframes
out a bit longer for a smoother
transition
to the louder part of the song
[Music]
next up is shortcuts for copy cut and
paste i use these all the time so
knowing the shortcuts really comes in
handy to copy you just need to hit
command c
if you want to cut you can hit command x
to paste the clip you can hit command
v or if you want to paste the attributes
like the effects the color grade
you can hit command option v and that is
going to add
everything from your clip to this next
clip but let's say you want to add
everything
but the crop what you can do is hit
shift command v and this is going to
paste your attributes from here
you can select what you want to copy
over to the next clip or not
so i want to add in all these effects my
entire color grade
but i don't want to add in my crop i'll
select that so it is not selected
anymore i'll go ahead i'll hit paste now
my color grade has copied over to this
clip without adding a crop
now let's say you've copied and pasted
all your effects onto
all your clips in your video but now
you're going through and you want to
change something
instead of going through clip by clip
and deleting something like an
eq what you can do is select all the
clips
and now you're going to hit shift
command x and now you can remove
attributes and so i'm going to select
the eq get rid of that
i'm going to hit remove and now that
clip does not have the eq added onto it
these tools
definitely work best in bulk when you
are selecting multiple clips and adding
and subtracting attributes from them now
for this next one i use this every
single time i edit a youtube video when
i'm ready to start editing the audio i
go up here and before i actually start
messing with the eq
i put the clip that i want to edit on a
loop
all you have to do is hit the forward
slash and if your playback is set to
loop which you can change that in your
settings
then it is going to loop once it reaches
the end of the clip
every time you color grid you really
should be looking at your scope so
hitting command 7
is going to pull that up and then
hitting command 7 again is going to get
rid of it when trimming a clip you could
hit
b and then hit a again select the clip
you want to delete and that is going to
trim it off
but there's actually a faster way to do
it if you know this is the end
of your clip and you want the rest of it
to be gone you can hit option
close bracket and that is going to
automatically delete the rest of the
clip for you holding down option and
hitting
open bracket is going to do the same
thing on the other end trimming the
beginning of the clip
if you temporarily want to disable
something on your edit you can hit
v and that will remove it without
deleting it and you can do the same
thing
with an audio file so you can watch it
back without the audio without deleting
your audio and then hitting v again
is going to bring those assets right
back if you want to just listen to an
audio track instead of disabling all the
sound effects and audio in the video
what you can do is select the video or
audio track that you want to listen to
and hit option
s on your keyboard and option s to bring
it back and you can do this with
multiple clips so if we want to select
both of these clips and hit option s
that is going to disable everything else
and solo out just these tracks so we can
listen to these
only have you ever done something you
did not want to do and you wanted to go
back like delete your entire project
well you just have to hit command
z and that is going to bring it right
back now if you want to redo what you
did instead of
undoing you can hit shift command z and
that is going to
redo what you just did click on the
screen to watch another final cut pro 10
tutorial and i'll see you guys in the
next
[Music]
video